<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Cloudnoise</title>
 <link href="http://zimok.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://zimok.github.com"/>
 <updated>2013-05-22T20:01:12+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://zimok.github.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Cloudnoise</name>
   <email>simonecarella@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The agony of hope</title>
   <link href="http://zimok.github.com/blog/the-agony-of-hope"/>
   <updated>2013-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://zimok.github.com/blog/the-agony-of-hope</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hope you noticed the quote from &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Pennac'&gt;Daniel Pennac&lt;/a&gt; on the sidebar (or the header). If you don&amp;#8217;t know a little bit of French, it asserts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Parameter's list is the agony of hope. Nothing will ever work fine
if you think about everything it needs to work fine&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sentence is becoming like a mantra. Because it is, and it has been, unquestionably true, at least for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our minds are full of schemes to follow. We can&amp;#8217;t live without those parameters lists. We&amp;#8217;re attaching them on the wall. We&amp;#8217;re repeating them mumbling, with the same meticulousness a practicing catholic recites the rosary. It seems we won&amp;#8217;t start anything without assuming that we have to religiously take the pattern &lt;em&gt;XYZ&lt;/em&gt; in order to get everything done in &amp;#8220;the right way&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take whatever guide, book, ux fellow, design guru. They&amp;#8217;re basically telling you how to do things. They&amp;#8217;re telling you to do things in one way. That one way. I&amp;#8217;m personally a skeptical by nature. I don&amp;#8217;t believe them. Or, better, I believe that what they&amp;#8217;re telling me to do, works fine for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not referring to a particular technique, pattern, process. I&amp;#8217;m not saying that your technique will fail as is. I&amp;#8217;m saying that your technique it&amp;#8217;s likely going to fail if applied to the wrong context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, there&amp;#8217;s no definitive process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My process changes given two main variables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the product&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;my current mood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id='several_contexts_several_processes'&gt;Several contexts, several processes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same workflow will never work the same way for every different product we are building. Moreover, a product is made of several contexts and, the deeper we go into them, the sooner we&amp;#8217;ll recognize how is it difficult, if not impossible, to apply the same pattern for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is due to the nature of the &lt;strong&gt;medium&lt;/strong&gt; we build for. User needs raises and changes as the medium does. Design processes too. We can simply predict, but never be sure to know what all this thing called &lt;em&gt;web&lt;/em&gt; will become tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we can simply adapt ourselves &amp;#8211; and all our theoretical luggage &amp;#8211; to adhere to the medium and its ecosystem. Not the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='imperfect_by_nature'&gt;Imperfect by nature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, there&amp;#8217;s the mood. It seems that nobody take in consideration the psychological side. This assumes that we&amp;#8217;re like robots, and that we work like a robot in an assembly line, without any superstructure conditioning our daily job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, it&amp;#8217;s likely that what I&amp;#8217;m designing will be heavily influenced by how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perfect workflow should be conformable to us human beings, so it should be imperfect by nature, like we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: the perfect workflow still does not exist, and never it will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I simply feel there are some moments I&amp;#8217;m confident with a process, and I rely on it. Other times, I like to make the process driven by my &lt;strong&gt;sentiments&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And never let an aseptic list of parameters kill them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: this could be applied for everything in the life&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>